australia.gov.au 2015-03-17

# Privacy policy | australia.gov.au

Thank you for visiting **_australia.gov.au,_** an online service managed by the Department of Finance, located in Canberra, ACT. We respect and protect the privacy of our users. This privacy policy tells you how we collect and use information.

The term "Personal Information" in this privacy policy means any information from which your identity is apparent or can be reasonably ascertained. We do not collect Personal Information about you when you visit this online service.

You can use this service without telling us who you are or revealing other Personal Information. If you send us a contact or feedback form you do not need to identify yourself or use your real name.

## Scope

The purpose of this online service is to provide you with trusted information from Australian, state and territory government sources.

## Personal information

If you contact us we will collect the email address you nominate and any other identifying information you provide, such as a name or phone number.

Please do not give us other personal or sensitive information.

Other than circumstances such as unlawful activity or serious threats to health and safety, we do not share Personal Information with other government agencies. If you ask us about an issue that needs to be dealt with by another agency, we will provide you with the necessary details to make contact yourself. You may opt out of further contact from us at any time.

## How we deal with complaints and requests

You may request access to Personal Information about you that we hold and you may ask us to correct your Personal Information if you find that it is not accurate, up-to-date or complete. You may also make a complaint about our handling of your Personal Information. These services are free of charge.

To protect your privacy and the privacy of others, we will need evidence of your identity before we can grant you access to information about you or change it.

You can contact us by email, or send your request or complaint to the postal address below. We undertake to respond within 30 days. If the request or complaint will take longer to resolve, we will provide you with a date by which we expect to respond.

## How we protect your Personal Information

This online service is hosted in Australia in secure, government accredited facilities. To help protect the privacy of data and personal information we collect and hold, we maintain physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis.

We train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information. Access to your Personal Information is restricted to employees who need it to provide benefits or services to you.

## Website analytics

To improve your experience on our site, we may use 'cookies'. Cookies are an industry standard and most major web sites use them. A cookie is a small text file that our site may place on your computer as a tool to remember your preferences. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

Our website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. When you go to other websites from here, we advise you to be aware and read their privacy policy.

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or [use the opt-out service provided by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

_australia.gov.au_ also uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to "like" or "share" information from this website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your visits to this site with other Personal Information

## Our obligations

This online service is bound by the provisions of the [_Privacy Act 1988 (Cth)_](http://www.comlaw.gov.au/Series/C2004A03712), including the [Australian Privacy Principles](http://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-act/australian-privacy-principles) _._

We also follow the [Guidelines for Federal and ACT government websites](http://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-resources/privacy-guides/guidelines-for-federal-and-act-government-websites%20%20) issued by the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](http://www.oaic.gov.au/).

## Contact us

Contact us about your privacy concerns.

Alternatively, you can write to us at:

Manager, australia.gov.au  
Technology and Procurement Division  
Department of Finance  
John Gorton Building  
King Edward Terrace  
Parkes ACT 2600  
Australia
